Hello there, we are so glad you're taking this course and we think you're gonna have all a whole lot of fun work in your way through it
No matter what brought you here
Whether this is your first time exploring a computer platform where you're 9th or 12th
The mainframe environment is all of IT in one place and a career here will keep you engaged learning and current in all of it
And don't worry if you've never seen logged into or even thought all that much about mainframes before
We assume you're here to get started and that's where we'll begin
This course is everything I wish someone had sat me down and explained to me
Back when I first got started back in the early 2000s and a lot has changed since then
And a lot has changed since the first time this course came out
Which is why I'm back with my pal Mackenzie. Hi Mackenzie
Hey Jeff
How's it going?
We're gonna go in and freshen up a couple of the videos to bring them up to date
We want to talk about some new features new hardware and new approaches to problem-solving
We're so glad you're here to learn because now more than ever it's all about transactions
Massive massive amounts of secure transactions for stuff like paychecks health care insurance your phone your credit card your bank account the internet
And those are transactions that are powered by these systems
The hardware and software behind it all is expected to always be available
Ready to react and scale to whatever the world throws at it all that while protecting the data at the heart of it all
If you're new to all this you literally couldn't pick a better time to get started
There's so much going on we're in an era of specialized AI processors
They will let us do things nobody ever thought was possible just a few years ago
So we'll build up to the big fancy application level stuff
But we'll also make sure to start with the real fundamentals because once we've got those everything
We build on top of that. We'll just lock into place
The best thing is we're going to be teaching you skills that will absolutely differentiate you from others
You'll be able to put these skills to use from day one
So when you get brought in for a job interview
You'll have the confidence of not just knowing the technology
But understanding how that technology comes together to form solutions
That right there is what builds confidence. Oh, yeah, and you know, it's going to make you feel really confident
How about logging into a real live system with your own ID? I'm not talking about a simulation or animated screenshots
We're going in
But before we do that we've got just two favors to ask of you
One grab a pen and some paper
Or your favorite notes app and just keep it handy for any time you hear something that catches your attention
No need to go much deeper
Just literally make a note of anything that you wished you had some more information about
Because when we're all done
You'll have a good list of areas that you might want to focus on
Either for follow-up education or for your career in mainframe systems
And a good next step might be to find people who work in those areas and give them a follow
We also ask that you set aside time
Not just to watch the videos and pass the quizzes
But to reflect on what we're talking about to occasionally
Literally hit pause and ask yourself did I really get that?
Sometimes getting up and walking around a little bit is the physical activity that helps us contextualize things
After getting hit with a wave of new information
Taking the time and respecting your time to learn and understand whether you're doing this by yourself or with others is key
If you try to rush through and only focus on passing the quizzes
You won't get that lasting knowledge which is needed to put it all in context
There's a reason we get to present this course to you
Like this and there's a reason we aren't just picking up a manual and reading it to you
We're putting it into easily understandable terms
We're picking our words very carefully and making sure you're fully on board before moving on to the next thing
Because in Z everything is interconnected
So get comfy, give your arms a stretch and let's get going. There's a whole lot to cover